[BlockChain as a service in other industry]
Definition: DEFINITION of 'Blockchain-as-a-Service (BaaS)'
https://www.investopedia.com/terms/b/blockchainasaservice-baas.asp
[Blockchain as a Service (BaaS) is an offering that allows customers to leverage cloud-based solutions to build, host and use their own blockchain apps, smart contracts and functions on the blockchain while the cloud-based service provider manages all the necessary tasks and activities to keep the infrastructure agile(민첩) and operational(가동/운용 준비를 갖춘).
 It is an interesting development in the blockchain ecosystem that is indirectly aiding the blockchain adoption across businesses.
 It is based on, and works similar to, the concept of Software As A Service (SaaS) model.]


1. FinTech
  1) 링카(LINKA), 블록체인 기반 결제 서비스 한국 첫 출시 2018.09.11 19:42
     http://www.zdnet.co.kr/news/news_view.asp?artice_id=20180911144713&lo=zv40
     토큰(token): network을 따라 돌아다니는 일련의 특별한 비트열
	         computer들은 network을 따라 순환하는 token을 자신이 잡았을 때에만 network에 message를 보낼 수 있다.
	         각 network엔 오직 단 한 개의 token만이 존재함으로써, 두 개 이상의 computer가 동시에 메시지를 전송할 가능성을 사전에 차단함.

    "협력하여 일하는 행위자들(coordinators) 간에 공유자원 접근에 대한 동기화를 보장하기 위해 전달되는 추상적인 개념"
     - 절대 복사될 수도, 손상될 수도 없으며, token을 가진 삶이면 누구라도 특정 자원의 배타적 접근이 허용되며, 그것을 통제할 수 있는 권한을 가지게 된다.
    
     <출처: http://soul0.tistory.com/414>
     <참조: https://velopert.com/2350>
  2) J.P. Morgan sees three potential long-term stock winners from blockchain
     https://www.cnbc.com/2018/11/08/jp-morgans-three-potential-winners-in-blockchain.html
     [J.P. Morgan’s bets for that disruption are “middleman displacement opportunities” and “Blockchain as a Service,” which the firm calls “BaaS.” In the bank’s coverage at least three names fit that criteria — Akamai, DocuSign and Ellie Mae.

      Cloud service provider Akamai, rated “overweight” by J.P. Morgan, could leverage the “BaaS” approach.

     “Rather than building from scratch we see customers looking to utilize a vendor like Akamai that offers its Blockchain capabilities as a service,” Auty said. “While there are a number of companies that have blockchain technology, IBM as one example, we believe the sizeable Akamai network is an inherent advantage in running a distributed ledger in blockchain.”

      In this case, J.P. Morgan is advocating for use of closed, permissioned blockchain, also known as just “private.” Bitcoin by comparison, is the biggest “public” blockchain meaning anyone can join or participate in that network. Its “distributed ledger,” where transactions are recorded can also be seen by just about anyone.

      DocuSign already offers the ability to connect a blockchain network to its systems. The company, which J.P. Morgan also rated “overweight,” could leverage both private and public blockchains.

      “DocuSign wants to be the platform to enable the entire contracting process in a digital manner. Over time we could see much of the platform being based on blockchain, basically shifting its
       centralized security model for the distributed model of blockchain, ” J.P. Morgan’s Auty said.]

    "public" vs. "private" blockchain
2. Market
  1) Supply Chain Management(공급만 관리)
     정의: https://m.blog.naver.com/PostView.nhn?blogId=copierrental&logNo=220694164026&proxyReferer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.co.kr%2F
     공급 망 전체를 하나의 통합된 개체로 보고 이를 최적화 하고자 하는 경영방식
     Main Issue topic : transparency(투명성 담보)
	https://medium.com/bitfwd/top-5-most-compelling-use-cases-for-blockchain-technology-d198e500e3d3
          
3. University[Scholar](imprimis (특별히) Education)
  1) 4 Ways Blockchain Could Change the Education System
     https://medium.com/@impactchainlab/4-ways-blockchain-could-change-the-education-system-988fc7c3db42
  2) 대학 교육과 블록체인 — 새로운 패러다임의 서막
     https://medium.com/@kblockresearch/12-대학-교육과-블록체인-새로운-패러다임의-서막-d60ac86db931
    ★★★★★ 
	      BLOCKCERTS Homepage - https://www.blockcerts.org/
                  https://github.com/blockchain-certificates
4. Manufacturing
5. Industrial Management
6. Politics
  1) election(투표)
     미국 중간선거에 블록체인 투표 도입
     http://www.zdnet.co.kr/news/news_view.asp?artice_id=20180808100213&from=Mobile
7. 의료
  1) 의료제등록(의료기록)
  2) Healthcare
     Main Issue topic : patient data held across different institutions in legacy siloss in various different formats and standards, making sharing of the data ill suited for the modern user’s expectation for instantaneous access.
	https://medium.com/bitfwd/top-5-most-compelling-use-cases-for-blockchain-technology-d198e500e3d3
8. 오락(Entertainment)
  https://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/2018/05/14/30-real-examples-of-blockchain-technology-in-practice/#6a76cd46740d
  1) 
  2)
  3) 
  4) 


----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
2018.11.22 18:07경
소스코드를 먼저 찾고 나서, 추후에 (욕심을 내서) 코드 수정까지 이어갈지 결정.
(분석과 기능 설명까지 이어가도 충분할 듯.)
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
2018.11.22 20:00경
[BLOCKCERTS GitHub Repository 담당]
1. 김성언
   1) pyld
      json : 데이터교환 형식 (javascript)
      ld : linked data
      json -> 파이썬으로 구현한 것 pyld
   2) archived-cert-store
      저장소
      사용자로부터 얻은 학위 파일을 통해 저장소에 있는 학위 파일 찾는 역할을 하는 함수 포함
      파이썬의 simplekv 인터페이스 이용
2. 조경연
   1) openbadges-validator-core
   다양한 입력 소스를 기반으로 open badges의 유효성을 검증하고 속성 및 유효성 검사 정보에 액세스 할 수 있는 유용한 인터페이스를 제공하는 패키지이다.
   발급자인 경우 오류를 식별하는데 필수적인 오류 메시지를 찾을 수 있다. 오류 메시지는 오류 위치를 식별하는 메시지의 node_id 또는 node_path를 대상으로 가능하다. (아직은 신뢰할 수 있을 만한 결과가 나오지 않음)
   2) cert-tools
      Create_certificate_template.py : 기본 인증서 템플릿을 만듦. 여기에는 받는 사람 관련 데이터 포함되지 않음.
      Instantiate_certificate_batch.py : 인증서 템플릿을 채운다. csv 파일의 값을 기반으로 수신자 별로 인증서를 생성한다.
      Create_revocation_addresses.py (아직 사용하지 않음) : 개인키를 사용하여 비트코인 주소를 생성함. 이것은 발급자가 나중에 특정 인증서를 취소할 경우에만 사용
   공개키(Public Key): 암호화 할 때의 키
   개인키(Private Key): 복호화 할 때의 키
3. 김덕한
   1) cert-schema
   - 파이썬 패키지
   - JSON 스키마에 대해 블록체인 인증서를 편리하게 인증 가능하게 도와줌
   - 블록체인에 저장된 인증정보를 인증하는 것과는 다르다
   2) cert-verifier
   - 블록체인 자격증을 입증하기 위한 라이브러리

   #verifier.py
      - 진실성 확인
      - 시그니처 확인
      - 취소, 만료 여부 확인
      - 입증성 확인
   #errors.py(작성되지 않은듯)
      - error 출력
   #connectors.py
      - 블록체인 네트워크에 접속
      - helping 거래내역 lookup
   #checks.py
      - verifier.py에 imported
      - updates from cert-core
   #__init.py__
      - 블록체인 거래내역을 찾을 경우 저장할 클래스 생성

4. 진수연
  cert-issuer
While it is possible to issue one certificate with one Bitcoin transaction, it is far more efficient to use one Bitcoin transaction to issue a batch of certificates.

The issuer builds a Merkle tree of certificate hashes and registers the Merkle root as the OP_RETURN field in the Bitcoin transaction.
블록체인 인증서 발급, 저장
인증서, 수취인 정보 저장. (트리 형태로)
거래 수수료를 bitcoin 또는 Ethereum으로 지불.
비트코인 발급 주소를 만들고, 발급받는다.

<주요 클래스(Core issuing classes)>
1. Issuer
-블록체인에서 발행할 데이터를 추출.

2. CertificateBatchHandler
-블록체인에서 발행할 인증서를 관리. (인증서가 올바른 형식인지 등의
인증서의 세부 정보 처리.)
★★★ transaction
★★★ the Merkle root
5. 변재영
  cert-core

{Cert-core repository}
This python library contains common Blockcerts models and accessors used by other Blockcerts python libraries.

JSON file: JavasScript Object Notation
: network를 통해 data를 주고받는 데 자주 사용되는 경량의 data 형식
      [구성요소(component)]
   1) name/value 형태의 쌍으로 collection 타입.
      다양한 언어들에서, 이는 object, record, struct(구조체), dictionary, hash table, 키가 있는 list, 또는 연상배열로서 실현 되었다.
   2) 값들의 순서화된 리스트.
      대부분의 언어들에서, 이는 array, vector, list, 또는 sequence로서 실현 되었다.

The certificate storage interface is 'simplekv 0.11.11(2018.11.22 기준)'.
simplekv 0.11.11: A key-value storage for binary data, support many backends.
For more detailed information, https://pypi.org/project/simplekv/
kv stands for 'key-value'
key: ??
구성(構成, Configuration): 정보 처리 시스템이나 네트워크를 그 기능 단위의 개수, 성질, 상호 접속, 기본적인 특성에 따라 편성하는 것, 또는 그렇게 편성된 상태. 편성의 대상에 따라 하드웨어 구성, 소프트웨어 구성 등으로 분류된다.
In communications or computer systems, a configuration is an arrangement of functional units according to their nature, number, and chief characteristics. Often, configuration pertains to the choice of hardware, software, firmware, and documentation. The configuration affects system function and performance.
격자 파일 시스템(Grid file system): a computer file system whose goal is improved reliability and availability by taking advantage of many smaller file storage areas.
File systems contain up to three components:

File table (FAT table, MFT, etc.)
File data
Metadata (user permissions, etc.)
A grid file System would have similar needs:

File table (or search index)
File data
Metadata

For more detailed information,
1) http://a4academics.com/be-seminar-topics/17-be-it-cse-computer-science-seminar-topics/35-gfarm-grid-filesystem
2) https://users.cs.fiu.edu/~zhaom/gvfs/index.html

hash: 본래는 '잘게 쪼개다'의 그림

1. 김성언	       - 3 Issuer hashes credential onto the blockchain 
   [발행기관(Issuer)에서 인증 operation(credential, transaction)을 블록체인 단위로 나누는 부분]
2. 조경연, 김덕한 - 2 Recepient accepts invitation, sending issuer their blockchain address
   [학생(Recepient)들이 발행기관(Issuer)의 요청을 받아들이고, 각자의 블록체인 주소를 보내는 부분]
3. 변재영, 진수연 - 1 Issuer invites recipient to receive a blockchain credential
   [발행기관(Issuer)에서 학생(Recepient)에게 인증 operation(credential, transaction)을 주는 부분]